--==圣城家园SCG字幕组bbs.cnscg.com==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 桃茜茜
翻译: 专采油菜花 dingolily ECHO~ DanTe袁 黑枫 justa
校对: 岸 harvey66
伊拉克首都 越来越多的广播陷入瘫痪状态 爆炸事件大规模发生
More airwaves silent and most explosions in the Iraqi capital.
Tikrit 萨达姆・侯赛因的故里
Further explosions are unfolding in Tikrit,
将发生更大规模的爆炸事件
which is Saddam Hussein's ancestral hometown,
还有类似爆炸造成的攻击...
as well as blows from similar explosions are unfolding...
就在几秒前 另一波大型冲击波席卷市区
Just a few seconds ago, another huge blast shook this city,
巡航导弹和空袭如落雨般
cruise missiles and airstrikes raining down here
无情而猛烈地冲击巴格达
in a relentless assault on Baghdad.
毫无疑问 战争已在今晚拉开帷幕...
There is no doubt tonight that war has begun...
伊拉克首都陷入动荡与恐慌中
and the Iraqi capital is experiencing shock and awe.
别带那个! 空间有限!
快点! 快! 我们必须立刻离开!
大家快下楼!
将军...
Al Rawi将军 长官 我们必须立刻离开
快!
Ayad 上车 我随后就来
Seyyed 把大家送到安全藏身处
让他们等我指令
是的 将军
绿色地带
前方359米 目标位置
Approaching target site three-five-niner.
好了 大家听好了
All right, everybody, listen up.
这是个军事储备点 在Diwaniya
It is a military storage site. Diwaniya.
情报机构估计 那里可能有神经性毒剂 窒息剂
Intel estimates possible nerve agents, choking agents,
活体病原菌和化学核弹头导弹
live pathogens, chemical-tipped missiles.
101分队已经待了整个上午 因此那里是安全的
101st has been here all morning, so the site is secure.
大家保持警惕 情况就是这样
Everybody stay focused. This is it.
报告长官 敌方开火 右方 100米
Shots fired, right side, 100 meters, sir.
遇袭 右方 100米
We got shots fired. Right side, 100 meters.
上 行动 行动!
Let's go. Move. Move!
好的 跟上
Okay. Go ahead.
哪位长官管的?
Who's the officer in charge?
走! 走! 走!
Move! Move! Move!
嘿! 由谁管的?
Hey! Who's in charge?
在这 我是Asira中尉
Right here. Lieutenant Asira.
我是Miller准尉 机动执行组Delta分队的
Chief Miller, Met-Delta.
这群趁火打劫的人到底在干什么?
What the fuck are all these looters doing here?
这里有大规模的杀伤性武器 需要特别保护
This is a WMD site. This is a high-priority site.
听着 我没有足够的人手来解决外围问题
Look, I don't even have enough men to set up the perimeter.
就在这栋楼里 有个狙击手
We got a sniper in this tower right here.
就是后面那座大楼?
In the big tower on the back?
就是后面那座大楼
In the big tower on the back.
我人手不足 无法闯入时确保那些化学品的安全
I do not have enough men to go in and secure the inside of that compound.
听着 听着 情报机构说这里有活化的化学药剂
Listen, listen. Intel says we got live chemical agents in this site.
好吧 我们立刻行动! 这帮强盗...
Okay, we gotta move now! These looters...
我真不知道这群人要搬走什么
I don't know what these people are carrying out right now.
我必须进到里面 我要进去
I gotta get into this site. I'm going in.
准尉 你不能进去
Chief, you can't go in.
你要是现在带队进去 后果自负
If you take your team in right now, it's on you.
集合集合 赶快 听着 情况是这样的
Gather around. Gather around. Come on. Listen, here's the situation.
101分队派来了35名士兵和1位少尉
101st sent 35 men and one butter bar down here.
他们并不能确保这里的安全 那么
They don't even have this place secure, so
这是我们现在的位置
here's where we are right now.
现在 武器就在建筑群的西北处
Now, the weapons are in the northwest end of the complex.
有个狙击手躲在那边的大楼里
There's a sniper holed up in the big tower there.
我们必须迅速把他干掉
We're going to have to quickly take him out.
我会带领一个侦察小队开路 我还需要内置自测仪
I'm going to take a recon element forward. I'm going to need C-BIST.
- Marshall和Johnson 你们跟着我  - 是的 长官
- Marshall and Johnson, you come with me.  - Yes, sir.
两名狙击手 Potts和Michaels 我还需要一个会炸弹拆除的
Two shooters, Potts, Michaels. I'm going to need EOD.
- Conway 再带上Simms  - 在这 长官
- Conway, bring Simms also.  - Right here, sir.
- 准备好了 准尉  - 没问题 待命
- Ready, Chief.  - All right, stand by.
准尉 我必须和你谈谈 这太糟了
Chief, I gotta talk to you. This is fucked.
听着 这里一片混乱
Listen, this is a disaster.
是乱成一团 安全毫无保障
It is a disaster. They haven't secured dick.
准尉 我认为我们还不该进去 应该等待更准确的情报
I don't think we should go in yet, Chief. Let's get some acceptable intel.
不不不 看看这! Jerry 我不知道将会发生什么
No, no, no. Look at this! Jerry, I got no idea what's coming out here.
我必须现在行动
I gotta go right now.
保持通讯畅通 我在第五频道
Keep comms open. I'll be on five.
让第二队待命
Get a second team ready.
我们走! 行动! 行动!
Let's go! Move! Move!
兄弟们 快把那垃圾从车上拿下去
Guys, get that shit off the truck now.
收到
Roger that.
- 内置自测仪呢?  - 在这 准尉
- C-BIST?  - Right here, Chief.
我要你跟在狙击手的后面 行吧?
I want you to stay right on the backs of your shooters, all right?
- 他们会掩护你进去  - 收到 准尉
- They will take you in.  - Roger that, Chief.
好的 准备好了吗?
All right. We ready?
- 是的 长官!  - 大家行动 快! 快! 快!
- Yes, sir!  - Let's go. Go! Go! Go!
行动! 行动!
Move! Move!
狙击手! 嘿 军士! 他在哪?
The sniper! Hey, Sarge! Where is he?
他就在那 但是我们没法进那条巷子
He's right up there, but we can't get down the alley.
好的 大家听好了
Okay, everyone, listen up.
Michaels! Michaels 听着 嘿!
Michaels! Michaels, listen. Hey!
大规模杀伤性武器就在这座大楼 你们需要一直绕到后门
The WMD are in this building. I need you to work your way to the rear door here.
看看是否能找到射击到狙击手的角度
See if you can get an angle on that sniper.
我要你带着内置自测仪 带上Simms 还有长步枪
I want you to take C-BIST with you. Take Simms, also, with the long rifle.
明白了 准尉
Got it, Chief.
嘿 我必须穿过这条巷子
Hey, I gotta get across this alley.
我需要火力掩护 没问题吧?
I need some cover fire, all right?
好吧
Okay.
当203小队过去的时候 我们也沿着相同的路线从左边过去
When the 203 goes, we're going to go all the way down on the left side.
- 好的 准备  - 收到 准尉
- All right. Stand by.  - Roger that, Chief.
我们走
Let's go.
机动执行组Delta分队 行动!
Met-Delta team, go!
行动 行动! 我们走!
Move, move! Let's go!
行动! 行动!
Move! Move!
我发现他了 他在5楼 东南角的房间
I got him, He's on the fifth floor, southeast corner room,
我逼他出来
I'm going to draw him out.
你一看见他 就干掉他
As soon as you see him, take him.
收到
Roger.
立刻! 马上! 快!
Now! Now! Now!
干掉他了吗?
Got him?
干掉了 你们三个出来
We got him. Three coming out.
Michaels 把内置自测仪送过去
Michaels, send C-BIST over.
走! 走! 走!
Go! Go! Go!
Potts Keating 走! 走!
Potts, Keating, go! Go!
第二小队 行动! 我们走! 前进! 前进!
Second team, move! Let's go! Move! Move!
前进!
Move it!
进去
In.
检查一下 我们来
Check. Check. Let's do it.
好的 拿出装置 所有人都进入全面防护状态
All right. Break out the gear. I want everyone in full MOPP.
现在听准尉指挥 准备好 粘紧胶条
Now you heard Chief. Get ready. Roll those seals tight.
明白
I got it.
这里未读取到任何信息 准尉
No readings in here, Chief.
好吧 Conway 打开
All right, Conway, open it up,
那里只有厕所用具
Nothing but toilet parts over here.
这是鸽子屎吗?
Is this all pigeon shit?
嗯 看起来在这放了大概有10年了
Yeah, thing looks like it's been here about 10 years.
嗯
Yep.
这没有大规模杀伤性武器
This is no WMD site.
收队
Pack it up.
嘿 准尉 找到了什么吗?
Hey, Chief, we find anything?
这里是空的
The site's empty.
待命
Standing by,
嘿 情报是哪来的?
Hey, where did that intel come from?
你要我为你在核查下目标代码吗? 可以
Do you want me to double check the target number for you? Because I can.
不用不用 我们找对了地方 示意图是对的
No, no, we're in the right location. The schematic's right.
但是示意图从哪来的? 我是说...
But who did it originate with? I mean...
嘿 这是从联合国来的吗?
Hey, did this come from the United Nations?
根据数据显示 准尉 是由我们的情报机构提供的
According to this data, Chief, this is our intel.
嗯 但是他们凭什么认为东西在那?
Yeah, but how would they think something was there?
又有正事了
This is the third straight time.
我们走
Let's go.
听准尉的 我们走
You heard the chief. Move out.
好了 收好东西 我们走
All right, pack this shit up and let's go.
收到!
Roger that!
我们走! 行动!
Let's go! Move!
上车 我们走
Step on it. Let's go.
萨达姆国际机场
Zubaidi在中间的直升机上 密切关注他一举一动
Zubaidi will be on the middle chopper. Get tight on his exit.
转过来 转过来
Swing it around. Swing it around.
美国国防部人员来这与他会面
The DOD guy's here to meet him.
从机场为您带来的实况报道...
Reporting to you live from the tarmac here...
准备好拍特写了吗? 走 走 走!
Ready for the close-up? Go, go, go!
那是美国国防部的Poundstone
That's Poundstone from DOD.
怎么样?
How's it going?
很好
Great day.
嗯 最终在这见到他了
Yup, you finally got him here.
嗯 我们觉得我们一直都有进展 那很重要
Well, we feel like we're making progress. That's important.
那么 武器的问题呢?
So, what about the weapons?
那也很让我沮丧
I'm frustrated by that, too.
我们尽己所能 我们将会找到武器 不必担心
We're doing everything we can. We'll find the weapons, don't worry about it.
全世界都在关注 他们想知道武器在哪
The whole world's watching. They want to know where they are.
我和Zubaidi一定要坐第一辆 好吗?
Make sure Zubaidi and I are in the lead car, okay?
Jack 我要你们都跟在后面
Jack, I want your guys to tail us.
明白 先生
You got it, sir.
- Clark!  - 怎么了?
- Clark!  - What?
我需要消息来源 我需要Magellan的消息
I need the source. I need Magellan.
你知道这问题有多敏感吗?
Do you have any idea how sensitive this is?
Magellan已经被彻底监禁了 我自己都不确定能联系到他
We've got Magellan locked up so tight, I'm not even sure I can get to him.
你是行政机构的核心管理人员 你不能联系到你自己线人?
You're the administration's go-to guy and you can't access your own source?
Lawrie 我们正在审问他
Lawrie, we're debriefing him.
这需要时间 要先来后到吧
It takes time. That comes first.
天哪 到目前为止从他那得到的消息 我都告诉你了
For Christ's sake, I've given you everything I got on the guy so far.
- 你还要些什么?  - 我不想从你这得知
- What more do you want?  - I don't want to hear it from you,
我想听他告诉我
I want to hear it from him.
我会再看看的
I'll see what I can do.
你好啊?
How are you?
- 欢迎回家 先生  - 我们做个简短的采访
- Welcome home, sir.  - We'll make this very brief.
回来的感觉怎么样 Zubaidi先生?
How does it feel to be back, Mr. Zubaidi?
你有没想过有这么一天?
Did you ever think you'd see this day?
我是伊拉克公民 应该能自由地回归故里
I'm an Iraqi citizen, returning free to the city of my birth.
我会邀请所有的伊拉克人民庆祝从暴政中解放
I call on all Iraqis to celebrate our liberation from tyranny.
好极了 有两名技工正在检查
Bravo one, we've got two mechanics taking a look at it,
核查结果为 顶部枪支发射情况良好
Tracking on the upgun is pretty well shot
通信链接全部短路
and the comm links are all shorted out,
换成了什么时段?
What's the time frame on a replacement?
我要小队列表 马上!
I want a squad list, now!
嘿 Bethel上校在哪?
Hey, where's Colonel Bethel?
他在后面 准尉
He's in the back, Chief.
谢谢
Thank you.
Roy 我在那边等你 怎么样?
Roy, let me meet you over here, okay?
好 我们那里见
Yeah, I'll meet you in there.
- 嘿 长官  - 很高兴见到你 准尉
- Hey, sir.  - Good to see you, Chief.
情报机构怎么了?
What's going on with the intel?
你现在不会想知道的
You don't want to get into that right now.
我们必须谈谈 那什么都没有 那些地点都是空的
Well, we gotta talk about it. There's nothing there. These sites are empty.
我们行动将要非常仔细
We're going to be very careful,
否则就会被扣上大屎盆
or there's going to be a huge shitstorm around here.
你什么意思?
What do you mean?
他们归咎于我们行动速度不够快
They're blaming us for not moving fast enough.
我们还得继续执行任务
We have to stay on task.
胡扯 情报不准
That's bullshit. The intel's no good.
冷静点 行吗?
Let's not make any waves, okay?
他们不想回华盛顿 再听到这句话
They don't want to hear that back in Washington.
他们所感兴趣的就是 找到些能堵住CNN嘴的东西
All they're interested in is finding something they can hold up on CNN.
长官 但是我们必须谈谈 情报是个问题
Sir, but we gotta talk about this. The intel is a problem.
现在还不是时候 准尉
Now is not the time, Chief.
呜! 起立!
Roo! On your feet!
请坐 各位
Take your seats, people.
今早在这 是来让将军审查
We're here this morning to give the General
我们搜索的可能藏有大规模杀伤性武器的场所
a check on where we are in our search for WMD
以及未来48小时我们的计划
and what our plans are for the next 48 hours.
为此 有请Jonathan Vaught上尉发言
To that end, I'm turning the floor over to Captain Jonathan Vaught.
上尉 长官
Captain. Sir.
欢迎各位
Welcome, sir.
今天 我将要简短地向你们说明 在未来的24小时
Today we're going to be briefing you on WMD operations due to take place
可能发生在巴格达以及其周边地区的大规模杀伤性武器行动
in and around the Baghdad area over the next 24 hours.
我们将继续将重点考虑的地点作为目标
We're continuing to target high-priority sites,
这是因为所有家人都焦急地等待着
since all the folks back home are anxiously awaiting the information
我们找到了这些武器的消息
that we found these weapons.
我们已经商量出缜密的媒体计划
We have a detailed media plan we've worked out.
我们已经和与公众事务相关的人们进行协调
We've coordinated with the public-affairs folks.
我们已有完善的计划 这涉及到
We have a good plan that involves the top-rated media
美国和英国一流的媒体
in the United States and the UK
因此他们准备好对好信息的各个方面进行报道
so that they're prepared to cover all aspects of the good news.
- 什么?  - 关于明天的情报
- Yeah?  - I had a couple questions
我有几个疑问
about the intel for tomorrow.
确定这是准确消息吗?
Are we sure this is accurate?
很可靠 行动没有问题
It's solid. It's good to go.
消息来源是什么?
What's the source?
呃 这是线人提供的情报
Well, it's a human-source intel.
但是这很可靠 4点刚拿到的
But it's solid. It's current as of 0400.
我们用过相同来源的情报吗?
Was it the same source we've been using?
我们抄剿每个地点时 都像无头苍蝇一样
Every site we've hit on the way up here, we've rolled a donut.
准尉 我们这么做如何? 待会再谈
Chief, how about we do this? Let's talk offline.
给我个清单 列上你去过的地方和坐标
Give me a list of the places where you went, and the grids,
我们会检查你写下的信息是否正确
and we'll make sure that you had the right information written down
去过的地方是否没错 好吗?
and that you went to the right places, okay?
上尉 问题不在于位置 问题是那儿什么东西都没有
Captain, the issue isn't the grids, sir. The issue's that there's nothing there.
暂停争论 准尉 我们得就此问题继续
Stand down, Chief. We need to move on here.
Don 暂停 暂停一下 让我们听听准尉的说法
Don, hold on. Hold a second. Let's hear what the chief has to say.
是 长官 举个例子
Okay, sir, I'll give you an example.
上周 我们进到了一个地点 在Diwaniya 知道吗?
We rolled into a site, Diwaniya, last week, okay?
为了给我们开路 101队还有队员受伤
101st took casualties securing it for us.
我们进去后发现那是个洁具工厂
We got in there and found it was a toilet factory.
我想说的是
I'm saying there's a disconnect
情报和我们实际看到的之间有差异
between what's in these packets and what we're seeing on the ground.
情报有问题 长官
There's a problem with the intelligence, sir.
事情是这样的 准尉
Here's the thing, Chief.
这些情报都是经过审查的
These intelligence packages have all been vetted.
没有问题
They're good.
你们的任务是执行 不用操心怎么来的情报
Your job's to execute them, not worry about how they're put together.
明白了?
Are we clear on that?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
好的 继续
Good. Let's continue.
长官 如我刚才所言 情报是凌晨4点才拿到的
Sir, as I was saying, the intel is as recent as 0400 this morning.
是可执行的 准确的
It's actionable and it's solid.
好的 接下来是 巴格达的Al Mansour
All right, next up is Al Mansour, Baghdad.
看起来像是地下仓库
It looks like it's some kind of underground storage site.
进到那座城市要走12公里开放的高速路
You got about 12 klicks of open highway to the city,
但路上状况很多
but there's a lot of activity on that road,
叫大家提高警惕
so tell everybody to keep their heads up.
好的
All right.
准尉?
Chief?
好的 我们要去找生化武器 明白?
All right. We're going to go chem. Yeah?
我去集合带头队伍 好吗?
I'm gonna get all the lead teams up, all right?
好 好的
Yeah, yeah.
我是中央情报局的 Martin Brown
Martin Brown, CIA.
我是Roy Miller
Roy Miller.
是的 我知道 我在会议上见过你了
Yeah, I know. I saw you at the meeting.
你要去巴格达的Al Mansour吧
You're going to the Al Mansour site in Baghdad.
- 是的  - 你在浪费时间
- Yeah.  - You're wasting your time.
联合国生物组2个月前去了那里
UN biological team hit it two months ago.
那儿什么都没有
There's nothing there.
混蛋
Fuck me.
这是我的名片 你说得对
Here's my card. You're right.
情报和事实有出入
This thing doesn't add up.
伊拉克人不打仗 不用大规模杀伤性武器
The Iraqis don't fight, they don't use WMD,
他们让我们进来却一无所获
they let us walk in here and find the goddamn cupboard's bare.
事有蹊跷
There's something wrong here.
我们得弄清楚
We gotta figure out what it is.
如果有所发现 给我电话
If you find anything, you've got my number.
确定 确定
That's affirmative, That's affirmative,
我们在后方四公里处遇到枪袭
We took on some fire about four klicks back,
但是火力很小 不用担心
pretty light, though, nothing to worry about.
哦 我得拍点照片
Oh, I gotta get some pictures of this.
随便
Be my guest.
抬头 来了
Heads up. Incoming.
该死的Potts 你个傻帽
Fucking Potts, you red-headed dick.
嘿 Wilkins 我是准尉 到这边来
Hey, Wilkins, this is Chief. Get up here.
来了!
Hold on!
唷 Kurry 赶快
Yo, Kurry, let's go.
退后 请退后
Please, get back. Please.
你去找几个人开开路
I want you to get a couple of the guys and clear out this traffic.
我们过于暴露了 得保持前行
We're too exposed out here. We gotta keep moving.
离车远点 先生 冷静
Back from the truck. Sir, take it easy.
拜托
Please.
拜托 靠边
Please, step aside.
请你把车移开 先生
I need you to move the vehicle, sir.
嘿 嘿 冷静
Hey, hey, relax.
放松!
Easy!
你他妈的别碰我!
Don't you fucking touch me!
妈的 我们走
Motherfucker, let's go.
- 嘿!  - 闭嘴
- Hey!  - Shut the fuck up.
滚开点!
Back the fuck up!
嘿! 嘿! 嘿 嘿 嘿 嘿!
Hey! Hey! Hey, hey, hey, hey!
怎么回事 中士?
What's going on, Sergeant?
准尉 他们很愤怒
Chief, they're pissed off.
说这儿没水 他们只想要水
They say there ain't no water. All they want is water.
对此我们无能为力
There's nothing we can do about that.
我们只是要前进
We just gotta get our vehicles moving.
你去把人都叫回车里
I want you to get the men back in the vehicles now.
嘿! 嘿!
Hey! Hey!
回车上去!
Get in the fucking car!
回去! 回车上去!
Get the fuck back! Get the fuck back in your vehicle!
离车远点 离车远点
Back from the truck. Get back from the truck.
- 别停  - 是的 长官
- Don't stop.  - No, sir.
临时联合政府总部 前萨达姆宫殿
好的 所以我们要召开伊拉克自由会议
Okay, so we're convening an Iraqi Freedom convention
明天在绿色地带举行
here inside the Green Zone tomorrow.
我们希望三大种族集团的代表
We are expecting to have representatives from all three main ethnic groups,
包括库尔德族 什叶派(穆斯林)和逊尼派(伊斯兰教)都参会 代表不同阶层的意见
the Kurds, the Shia and the Sunni, angling for different levels of power.
我们希望Ahmed Zubaidi
It is our hope that Ahmed Zubaidi
以领袖之姿出现
will emerge in a leadership position.
Ben 你对我们现在的状况满意吗?
Ben, are you satisfied that we're in a good place now?
我认为我们状况还不错
I think we're in a good place now,
不过可能还有些趁火打劫的情况
except for, perhaps, the press we're getting from this looting issue.
好的 我们暂且不提这个
Okay, well, let's table that for now.
说到稳定...
In terms of stabilization...
Zubaidi已经30年没来过这儿了
Zubaidi hasn't been here for 30 years.
但他是我们目前稳定局势的最佳人选
Well, he's the best bet we have right now for a stable democracy.
在巴格达 认识他的人不到10个
You find me 10 guys in Baghdad who even know who he is.
他是我们的朋友 Marty 他帮了不少忙
Well, he's our friend, Marty. He's been very helpful.
我们这边的人都很满意
Our office is extremely satisfied
他提供给我们的情报
with all the information that we've gotten from him.
Zubaidi这些年来一直卖垃圾情报给我们
Zubaidi's been selling us a crock of shit for years.
这家伙靠不住 他的情报不可靠
This guy is not reliable. His intelligence is not reliable.
他的线人也靠不住
His report chain is not reliable.
这就是人们对情报局失去信心的原因 Marty
This is exactly why people are losing confidence in the Agency, Marty.
你对每条情报都心存怀疑
You're questioning every single piece of intelligence that's coming in,
这样下去我们寸步难行
up to the point where we can't make any progress.
你不能把这个国家交给无人知晓的流放者
You cannot just hand this country over to an exile no one's ever heard of
和华盛顿的几个实习生
and a bunch of interns from Washington.
好吧 你是中东专家 Marty
Well, you're a Middle East expert, Marty.
如果你有更好的主意 为什么不现在就提出来?
If you got a better idea, why don't you just throw it out here on the table?
我们要利用伊拉克军队的帮助
We need to use the Iraqi army to help us.
这个国家是种族分歧的炸药桶
This country is a powder keg of ethnic division.
现在萨达姆完蛋了 他们是唯一能将这个国家聚在一起的力量
Now Saddam is gone, they're the only ones who can hold this place together.
我们不能以此说服美国人民
We're not selling that to the American people.
- 我们在和伊拉克军队打仗  - 好的
- We beat the Iraqi army.  - Right.
他们仍然在那儿 全副武装
Well, they're still out there and they're armed,
他们想在新伊拉克有立足之地
and they're looking for a place in the new Iraq.
够他们等的
They're going to be waiting a long time.
他们不是都追随萨达姆的
They didn't all follow Saddam.
如果我们让他们觉得值得的话
There are officers we can work with out there,
里面也有能与我们合作的军官
if we make it worth their while.
嘿 告诉你吧
Hey, let me tell you something.
美国花费了大量的金钱
We've spent too much American treasure
牺牲了很多生命
and too many American lives
才让叙利亚社会党上台
for us to put a Ba'athist general into a position of power.
你知道绿色地带外面正在发生的事情吗?
Have you any idea what's going on outside the Green Zone?
一团混乱 没有警察 每晚都有仇杀
It's chaos. No police, revenge killings every night.
人们质问我们为什么不能阻止这些
People are asking why we can't stop this.
- 我们正失去民心  - 民主造成的混乱
- We are losing the population.  - Democracy is messy.
民主造成的混乱
Democracy is messy.
如果你分裂这个国家 裁掉军队
If you dismantle this country and cut out the army,
六个月内就会有内战
you'll have civil war in six months.
我保证
I guarantee it.
好了 我们继续
Okay, let's move on.
兄弟们
我们得到消息 萨达姆逃跑了
美国人占领了这个国家
我们面临艰难的抉择...
我们的人正在待命
我们此时的决定将会决定伊拉克的未来
我们仍在AC3号路口守卫
We are continuing to hold at the intersection at Alpha-Charlie-three,
冷静!
Calm down!
听我说 拜托!
Listen to me, please!
听着 Wilkins中士!
Just listen. Sergeant Wilkins!
- 趴下!  - 我的胳膊!
- Get on the ground!  - My arm!
嘿 那边出什么事了 Wilkins?
Hey, what's going on over there, Wilkins?
准尉 那边有个当地人 发疯了
Chief, there's a local here, He's out of control,
Perry得搞定他
Perry had to tackle him,
我来了
I'm on my way.
好了 后退
All right, back up.
你他妈的趴好
You stay the fuck down.
- 怎么回事?  - 你弄伤我了!
- What's going on?  - You are hurting me!
出什么事了 中士?
What's going on here, Sergeant?
这个伊斯兰教徒说他有话要跟你说
This Hajji says he needs to talk to you about something.
我没招了 他一直这样
I have no idea. He goes on and on and on.
趴好了
Stay down.
你为什么这么做? 为什么?
Why are you doing this? Why you do it?
你能允许别人这么对你吗?
You agree someone do this to you?
嘿 Perry Perry
Hey, Perry. Perry.
让他起来 起来
You let him up. Let him up.
你允许?
You agree?
起来? 我可以起来了?
Up? I can stand up now?
你为什么这么做 啊? 凭什么?
Why you are doing this, huh? Why you are doing this?
你能允许别人这样把你的头按在土里?
You agree someone put your head in the dust like this?
你能允许别人这样对你? 这不公平!
You agree to be treated like this? This is not fair!
嘿 冷静
Hey, calm down.
我试着冷静 但这个家伙 把我按在地上!
I'm trying to calm down, but this guy, he put me on the floor!
你够了没?
Are you finished?
好了 够了
Yeah, I'm finished.
你叫什么?
What's your name?
我叫Farid Youssef Abdul Rahman 你可以叫我Freddy 好吗？
My name is Farid Youssef Abdul Rahman. You call me Freddy, okay?
我有情报 我在距这五分钟车程的地方
I have information. I was driving like five minutes from here.
看见一些人 你知道 像是萨达姆的人 像是叙利亚社会党的
I saw some people, you know, like Saddam's men, like Ba'athist people.
他们在开会 就在这附近开会
They are meeting. They have a meeting near to here.
我看见你们... 我不确定 你们在这儿找东西
I saw you are... I don't know, you're digging here,
- 就过来告诉你们  - 好 冷静 嘿! 嘿! 嘿!
- and I come to tell you.  - Okay, just calm down. Hey! Hey! Hey!
冷静 冷静
Calm down. Calm down.
我为什么要相信你 Freddy?
Why should I believe you, Freddy?
你觉得过来跟美国人说话容易吗?
You think it's easy to come and talk to American?
我容易吗? 我过来 这些人 都看着我?
You think it's easy? I come here, all these people, they're looking at me?
你们把我摁在地上 我想单独跟你说
You stick me on the floor. I want to speak to you quietly, huh.
你们在地上挖来挖去
And you are digging in the ground.
为什么要挖地?
Why you are digging in the ground?
你得跟这些人说明白 你知道他们怎么说吗?
You need to talk to these people. You know what they are saying?
你认为有人能在地里埋东西
You think someone can put something in this place
而所有这些旁观的人都不知道?
with all these people watching and all these people don't know?
这说不过去
It's not logical.
我是来帮你的 好吗 Miller?
I am here to help you, okay, Miller?
跟我来 Freddy 跟着我
Come with me, Freddy. Come with me.
准尉 没事吧?
Chief, you good?
是的 我很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
先生 请这边走
Sir, come this way, please.
嘿 准尉! 准尉 我们这是干嘛?
Hey, Chief! Chief, what are we doing?
嘿 我需要你的车钥匙 Freddy 把车钥匙给他
Hey, I'm gonna need his car keys. Freddy, give him your car keys.
我的钥匙?
My keys?
准尉 你不会相信这个家伙吧?
Chief, you don't believe this guy, do you?
听着 我想低调处理
Look, I wanna go real low-vis on this.
我想用Freddy的车 能再有一辆更好
I want to take Freddy's car and I want to get maybe one other.
如果我们开着悍马过去 他们会发现我们的
If we roll over there in those Humvees, they're going to see us coming.
我想带着Keating Potts和Bronner坐普通车
I want to take Keating, Potts, Bronner on comms.
你带着Michaels和探测器把Perry带过去
You gotta get me Michaels with the SAW and bring Perry over here.
怎么回事 准尉?
What's up, Chief?
嘿 准备好开工了吗?
Hey, you guys ready to go to work?
当然 准尉
Hell, yeah, Chief.
准尉 请让我跟你说句话
Chief, let me talk to you, please.
什么?
What?
准尉 我们的任务就是在这里
Chief, our mission is here.
怎么 你想就在这儿转转 整天挖坑?
What, you wanna sit around and dig holes all day?
我想做点儿有用的
I want to get something done.
好了 情况是这样
All right, here's the situation,
这个伊拉克人过来说有情报
This Iraqi just showed up with information
说有两三个头儿在这儿往西一点的地方
that about two or three "K" west of here,
现在正在开会
there's a meeting taking place right now,
很可能有重要目标人物
possible high-value targets involved,
所以我想采取行动
So I want to move on it,
第一辆车里 我想带着这个伊拉克人Freddy
In the first car, I want to take the Iraqi guy, Freddy,
Keating 你来开车 我来操作机关枪
Keating, you're going to drive, I'll ride shotgun.
Potts 你一直在后面掩护Freddy
Potts, you're in the back covering Freddy the entire time.
其余的人坐小货车 有问题吗?
The rest of you guys are going to roll in the pick-up truck. Any questions?
嘿 准尉 我们怎么知道这个家伙不会把我们带进埋伏?
Hey, Chief, how do we know this guy isn't leading us into a fucking ambush?
不知道
We don't.
收起你那张该死的夸张表情
Get your fucking game face on.
知道了
Roger.
- 明白了吧  - 明白了!
- Hooah.  -  Hooah!
- 好了 行动起来  - 你不让我开车 哈?
- All right, let's roll.  - You're not letting me drive, huh?
是的 你不开车
No, you're not driving.
武器就位
Weapons ready.
你叫Freddy 对吧? 我叫Potts 很高兴认识你
It's Freddy, right? I'm Potts. Nice to meet you.
发动车子!
Fire it up!
我们就要输了 到处都是美国人...
叛徒! 你就是个叛徒!
就是有你这样的害群之马 情况才会变成这样!
我?
像我这样的害群之马?
瞎了你的狗眼啊!
美国人现在居然把我们的权利转交给什叶派和库尔德人
我们现在必须反抗!
我们要怎么和美国人打?
趁现在还不晚 我们要反击!
同志们...
现在街上到处处于无政府状态
暴力事件不断增加...
如果美国人想在这儿推行民主的话
他们最终会意识到我们的重要性
那时候他们会向我们求助...
而我们就可以乘机就国家未来达成协议
先生...
如果他们不跟我们联系呢?
那样的话...
我们就开战
好了 Perry军士 你继续开
Okay, Sergeant Perry, I want you to carry on straight.
你在下个路口左转 绕回后面
Take your next left, and go around the back.
知道了 长官
Roger that, Chief.
在这儿停下 就是街角的那栋房子
And if you stop here, it is the house on that corner.
好了 就在这儿停车 就停在这儿
Okay, pull up here. Pull up here.
好了 注意了 就是东南街角的那栋
Okay, be advised, it is the house on the southeast corner.
砌着围墙的白色大宅子
The big white house with the wall.
注意点 有人出来了
Heads up. Someone's coming out.
有六到七个人手里拿着枪
There were six or seven men with guns.
好的 发现一个手里拿着公事包的人 还有一个端着AK-47枪的人
All right, we got a guy with a briefcase and another with an AK-47.
Perry 你在哪里? 到位了吗?
Perry, where are you? You in position?
已到位 准尉 发现目标
In position, Chief. We got them.
黑色宝马车里有三个人
Black BMW with three men.
先跟上宝马车
I want to take the BMW.
他一开进我们的车道 我们就拿下他
As soon as he comes up our way, we're going to cut him off.
先拿下宝马车里的人 再搞定房子里的 行动起来
I want to take the BMW and then the house. Go, go, go.
快 快 快!
Go, go, go!
出来! 马上出来!
Out of the fucking car! Get the fuck out of the car, now!
Perry 到那个门边守着
Perry, get on that door.
那个门
Get on that door.
把他捆起来 Bronner 你看着他
Zip him up. Bronner, stay with him.
其他人 快 快 快!
Everybody else, go, go, go, go, go!
跟上 跟着我
On me. Stack on me.
我们走! 我们走! 行动!
Let's go! Let's go! Go, go, go!
趴下 马上!
On the fucking ground, now!
好了 下去 到下面去
All right, down, down, down.
安全! 这边安全!
Clear! This side clear!
没找到 后门在哪里? Michaels 跟着我!
I've got no exit. Where's the back door? Michaels, with me!
Keating 上楼!
Keating, on the stairs up!
楼下 Michaels 跟我下去! 在下面!
Stairs down. Michaels, come with me down! Down!
明白 准尉
With you, Chief.
开枪!
Taking fire!
小心!
Look out!
注意 小心右边
Get ready to hook right.
小心右边!
Hook right!
我上去
I got stairs up.
安全 这边安全
Clear. It's clear.
我是准尉 汇报战况
This is Chief. Give me a sit rep.
我是Potts 一人受伤
This is Potts, got one wrapped up,
Keating 前院已安全
Keating, all clear out front,
准尉 我是Perry 上面需要紧急援助
Chief, this is Perry, I need you up here right away.
来了!
Coming in!
- 没事的 你老公没事的  - Perry!
- It's okay. Your husband is okay.  - Perry!
准尉 您瞧 得想想办法
Look, Chief, you gotta do something.
他们不懂我他妈在说什么啊
They don't understand what the fuck I'm saying.
这位是母亲 那位也是母亲 够了! 够了
This is the mother, that's the mother. Enough! Enough.
告诉她冷静 说 "冷静"
Tell her to calm down. Say, "Calm down."
准尉 我不知道她在说什么 她说的是方言
I don't understand her, Chief. It's a different dialect.
别让她走 所有人都不能离开
Don't let her leave. Don't let any of them leave this room.
楼下有个懂方言的人 别让他们走
There's a body down there. Don't let them leave.
知道了 长官
You got it, Chief.
夫人 你不能下楼
Ma'am, you can't go downstairs.
你不能下楼 呆在这里
You cannot go downstairs. Stay down.
闭嘴! 闭嘴!
Shut up! Shut up!
Potts 自己多加小心
Watch yourself, Potts.
把Freddy叫来 让他站起来 我有话要问
Get Freddy in here. Stand him up. I gotta talk to him.
Freddy 过来
Freddy, come here.
- 这不是我想要的结果  - 嘿 我要你...
- I don't want this.  - Hey, I need you to...
我告诉你情报 但我不想要这样的结果
I come to you for information. I don't want this.
你瞧 我需要你帮我问他几个问题
Listen, I need you to ask him questions for me.
告诉他你是我的翻译
Tell him you're my translator.
问他... 嘿 这是什么鬼东西?
Ask him... Hey, what is this shit?
这是什么? 他身上的吗?
What is this? Is this on him?
是的 他口袋里掉出来的
Yeah, that was fucking in his back pockets.
他说他什么都没做
He says he doesn't do anything.
问他叫什么名字
Ask him his name.
他叫Seyyed Hamza
His name's Seyyed Hamza.
Seyyed Hamza 这是他家吗?
Seyyed Hamza. Is this his house?
这是你家吗?
Is this your house?
嘿 告诉他最好回答我的问题
Hey, listen, tell him he's gonna answer my questions
否则后果不堪设想
or things are going to go very bad for him.
问他这里刚刚在秘密协商什么
Ask him what the meeting was about.
准尉 我刚刚接到电话
Chief, I just got off the phone.
这房子是Mohammed Al Rawi将军的
That license plate belongs to General Mohammed Al Rawi.
梅花J号通缉犯
The Jack of Clubs.
给我闭嘴!
Shut the fuck up!
嘿 Michaels 你带了那副通缉犯扑克牌吗?
Hey, Michaels, do you have that deck of cards?
带着呢
Yes.
给我梅花J
Give me the Jack of Clubs.
是那个人吗? 是那个从后门逃走的人吗?
Is that the guy? Was that the guy that went out the back?
准尉 给你
Here it is, Chief.
给我看 给我看看
Let me see. Let me see.
- 是那个人吗?  - 是那个人 我刚见到的就是他
- Is that the guy?  - That's the guy. I just saw this guy.
- 胡扯!  - 就是那个人
- Bullshit!  - That's the fucking guy.
我刚刚在楼下看到他
I just saw him downstairs.
这个人 就是萨达姆手下的一级将军
This man. This is Saddam's top general.
Al Rawi? 你知道他是谁吗? Al Rawi?
Al Rawi? You know who this is? Al Rawi?
他说他不知道
He say he don't know.
Al Rawi在这栋房子里?
Al Rawi's in this house?
这就是我看见的那个人
This is the guy I saw.
好了 好了 没时间了 好了 叫大家准备 我们撤
Okay, okay. Time's up. Okay, get everybody ready. We're leaving.
好了 他一定知道大规模杀伤性武器在哪儿 把他带走
All right, he's got to know about WMD. He's coming with me.
嘿 Freddy 你跟我过来
Hey, Freddy, I want you to come with me.
- 嘿 Michaels!  - 怎么了 长官?
- Hey, Michaels!  - What's up, Chief?
把他们都带到墙角那边
Bring them all over to the wall.
Potts 你把人都带过来 带到我那边去
Potts, I want you to get the guy. Get the guy and bring him to me.
知道了 准尉
Roger that, Chief.
- 让他们都靠墙坐着  - 是 准尉
- Just sit him down against the wall.  - Yes, sir.
让那些人坐在那里
Sit those guys over there.
到这儿来 Freddy 来给我翻译
Come over here, Freddy. Come here. I need you to translate.
告诉他我想知道大规模杀伤性武器的事
Tell him I want to know about weapons of mass destruction.
他知道那些武器在哪里吗?
Does he know where the weapons are?
什么? 什么? 关于那些武器你都知道些什么?
What? What? What do you know about weapons?
那些武器在哪儿?
Where are the weapons?
他说只有Mohammed Al Rawi将军知道武器的详细情况
He say only General Mohammed Al Rawi, he know about these things.
这个特殊计划由他自己亲自执行
The special program is under his hand personally.
他是唯一一个知道实情的人
He's the only one who know the truth about these things.
好 那我怎么才能找到Al Rawi?
Okay, how do I find Al Rawi?
Al Rawi在哪里?
How do I find Al Rawi?
他问 你们能保证他的家人安全吗?
He said, can you protect his family?
"只要你能保护我的家人 我就告诉你Mohammed Al Rawi将军在哪里"
"If you protect my family, I will tell you how you find Mohammed."
"从他那里 你就能知道实情了"
"And then from him you will know the truth."
好的 就这么说定了
Okay, he's got a deal.
问他关于这本书的事
Ask him about the book.
这写的是什么? 密码? 路线图? 地图?
What is it? Is it codes? Is it diagrams? Maps?
什么鬼东西?
What the fuck?
好的 Scotty 去那边
All right, Scotty, head on down there.
- Shorty 把他们带走  - 是的 长官
- Shorty, bag them and parade them.  - Yes, sir.
- 嘿 你是Miller?  - 是的
- Hey, you Miller?  - Yeah.
另外两个在哪里?
Where are the other two?
两个什么?
Two what?
我们丢了两个兵
We're missing two pucks.
- 有人看到那两个兵吗?  - 别 别 别!
- Anybody got eyes on the other two pucks?  - No, no, no!
这些是我的人 等等 等等 这些是我的犯人
These are my guys. Hold on. Hold on. These are my prisoners.
现在是我的犯人了
My prisoner now.
嘿! 那是我的翻译! 那是我的翻译啊!
Hey! That's my translator! That's my translator!
这他妈是怎么回事?
What the fuck is going on?
上校在等着这批犯人
I got a colonel waiting on these guys.
我现在就要送他们回去
I got orders to get these guys back there.
他们现在就该上路了
They're on route right now.
嘿 老大 冷静点
Hey, white bread, calm down.
这事儿你们的人碰不得 懂吗?
This goes way up higher than your people, all right?
请站在这里
Please, stand right there.
快点 这些犯人是我们的了
Come on. That prisoner's ours.
嗯 他是我们的了 走
Well, he's mine now. Let's go.
照顾我的家人!
Take care of my family!
他们在干嘛呢?
What they are doing?
我什么都没做!
I did nothing!
书! 他拿了我的书!
The book! He's got my book!
准尉 这他妈的是怎么回事?
Chief, what the fuck's going on?
他妈的!
Fuck!
是啊 我们抓住他 他说有人拿走了他的书
Yeah, I got him. He says some guy took a book off him.
书? 好吧 笔记本
Book? All right, all right. Notebook.
他说了关于书什么的
He says something about a book.
他的什么?
His what?
你拿了他的书 他说你他妈的拿了他的书
You got his book. He says you got his fucking book.
你拿了那个人的笔记本吗? 别耍花样
Do you have the guy's notebook? Don't fuck around.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
你他妈的别碰我 神经病
Get your fucking hands off me, asshole.
Miller 快把那本破书给我
Just give me the fucking book, Miller.
好了
All right.
别敬酒不吃吃罚酒!
I fucking asked you nicely!
去你的! 我才没有什么破书呢!
Fuck you! I don't have a fucking book!
干得不错
Have a nice war.
好吧 我们撤!
All right, let's get out of here!
放开我!
Get off me!
嘿!
Hey!
Freddy呢?
Where's Freddy?
- 你是说那个瘸子?  - 是的
- You mean the guy with the limp?  - Yeah.
他朝巷子那边跑了
He went over by the alleyway.
奶奶的! 我以为你们看着他呢
Fuck! I thought you were watching him.
- 我的枪呢? 我的枪呢?  - 这儿呢 给!
- Where's my weapon? Where's my weapon?  - Right here!
我把书给他了 我把那本书给他了!
I gave him the book. I gave him the fucking book!
Potts Michaels 去追他! 快! 走! 走!
Potts, Michaels, go with him now! Go! Let's go! Let's go!
Bronner 嘿! 快跟上!
Bronner, hey! Come on!
行动!
Moving!
快! 快!
Go! Go!
绕过去! 堵住他! 堵住他!
Go around! Seal it! Seal it!
知道了 准尉!
You got it, Chief!
Potts 发现目标
Get him, Potts.
左边! 去 堵住他
Go left! Go, seal it, seal it.
我看到他了! 站住!
I got him! Stop!
站住!
Stop!
抓住他! 抓住他! 抓住他!
Get him! Get him! Get him!
他妈的! 他妈的! 他奶奶的! 你跑什么?
What the fuck! What the fuck! What the fuck! Why are you running?
你们追什么?
Why you are chasing me?
书给我
Give me the book.
快他妈的把书给我!
Give me the fucking book!
书在这里 书在这里
Here the book. Here the book.
你为什么... 你在做什么? 我只是想保住这本书
Why are you... What you are doing? I was going to bring the book back.
那个坐在直升机里攻打伊拉克的人 他在打你
The man is putting Iraqis in the helicopter. He hit you in the face.
我还能怎么办?
What you want me to do?
我还要怎么做你才能相信我?
What I have to do for you to believe me?
把所有人都带到卡车那边去
Get everyone back to the trucks.
知道了
Roger.
嘿 走吧 走吧
Hey, let's go. Let's go.
我还要为你做什么? 哈?
What more I have to do for you? Huh?
我给你带来情报 你去了 情报是对的
I come to you with information. You take the information, it's right.
你要那本书 我有 也给你了
You want the book. I have the book. I give you the book.
你认为我能少了我的假肢?
You think I can leave my car?
你知道这条腿 它对我来说意味着什么吗?
You know what this car, it means to me?
我都把最关键的都给你们了!
Even you have the key!
你腿怎么了?
What happened to your leg?
丢在伊拉克战场上了
My leg is in Iran.
1987年就丢了
Since 1987.
我也为我的祖国而战
Me, too, I fight for my country.
Freddy 你瞧 你给了我们重要情报
Freddy, listen. You give me your information.
我们为你今天的所作所为 给你报酬的
I'm going to get you a reward for what you did today.
报酬?
Reward?
你们认为我这是为了钱?
You think I do this for money?
你觉得我不关心我的祖国吗? 我看着她遭受战火纷飞
You think I don't care about my country? I see what's happening.
你觉得我对这一切视而不见吗?
You don't think I see what's happen in it?
现在所有的人 甚至都没有水
And all the people now, even they have no water,
they have no electricity.
也没有电
你却觉得我这是为了赏金?
You think I do this for reward?
你难道不觉得我是为了我自己?
You don't think I do this for me?
为了我的将来? 为了我的国家? 为了这一切?
For my future? For my country? For all these things?
不管你想做什么 我都比你更想把它做好
Whatever you want here, I want more than you want.
我想帮助我的国家
I want to help my country.
哪位?
Who is this?
嘿 我是Miller准尉
Hey, this is Chief Miller,
我这有点东西 我想你应该会感兴趣
I have something I think you'd be interested in.
听着 我没时间跟你玩游戏 直接告诉我你有什么吧
Listen, I don't have time to play games, Just tell me what you've got,
好吧 今早我可是跟Mohammed Al Rawi见了一面
Well, this morning I came face to face with Mohammed Al Rawi.
你说Al Rawi将军?
General Al Rawi?
对 那个梅花J
Yeah, the Jack of Clubs.
来找我谈谈
Come in and talk to me,
我在绿区 共和国宫殿 游泳池旁边
I'm in the Green Zone, Republican Palace. By the pool.
我这就来
I'm on my way.
嘿 Wilkins中士 我得跟你谈谈
Hey, Sergeant Wilkins, I gotta talk to you.
我们得把我们的犯人带回来 然后再找出这个Al Rawi
We gotta go get our prisoner back, find this guy, Al Rawi.
就让Bethel去处理吧 拜托
Let Bethel handle it, please.
不行 Bethel对过往文件从不过问的
No. Bethel can't see past the files on his desk.
所以 你就这么直接去敲特种部队的门
So, what, you're going to ring the doorbell now
- 然后请他们把他交给你?  - 不
- and ask Special Forces to hand him over?  - No.
我得利用这本书 弄点高层内幕 以期有所帮助
I'm going to use the book and trade up and get some help.
你说的是什么意思?
What are you talking about?
Jerry 这些情报为什么总让我们扑空?
Jerry, why the fuck do we keep coming up empty on all these sites?
肯定是有原因的
There has gotta be a reason.
准尉 我们只是想完成任务然后安全回家
Chief, we're here to do a job and get home safe.
仅此而已 原因之类的 无所谓
That's all. The reasons don't matter.
但我有所谓
They matter to me.
恕我直言 准尉 这事我帮不了你
With all due respect, Chief, I can't go with you on this.
好吧 我会把队伍分开
Understood. I'm going to split the team.
我带上我的小队加上Perry中士
I'm going to take my crew plus Sergeant Perry.
你带着其他人去回Bethel报告 明白?
You report back to Bethel with everyone else, hooah?
明白
Hooah.
嘿 Freddy 想来帮忙吗?
Hey, Freddy. You want a job?
好吧
Yes.
很好 开上你的车 跟着我们
Good. Get in your car, follow us.
去哪 准尉?
Where to, Chief?
共和国宫殿
Republican Palace.
现在可不是好时候啊 Lawrie
This is not a good time, Lawrie.
我等得可够久了
I've waited long enough.
告诉过你 我已经尽力了
I told you, I'm doing the best I can.
这可不是我该做的啊 Clark
This is not what I signed up for, Clark.
我的声誉和这些故事系于一线
I put my reputation on the line with these stories.
我可不会让你这么坑害我
I am not going to let you hang me out to dry.
你看 我这还有紧急的事要处理
Well, there's huge things at stake here.
我可不能因为你要卖什么新闻而把大事给耽误了
I'm not going to let them be compromised because you need to sell some newspapers.
不是都说好了 我告诉你Magellan 你不能讲出我的名字
You knew the deal. I give you Magellan, you give me anonymity.
听着 Clark 我等够了 报社也等够了
Listen, Clark, I'm done waiting, so is the paper.
要是你不帮我找Magellan 我就让别人帮我找
You won't help me find Magellan, I'm going to find someone who can.
就在这儿
Right here.
- 再给我来点啤酒好吗?  - 飞盘来了!
- Can you get me some more beers?  - Frisbee!
哦 该死!
Oh, shit!
哦 我的老天啊 我们还有时间干这些?
Oh, my goodness. We got enough time for that?
这些人吃着达美乐比萨还喝着冰啤酒?
These guys got Domino's Pizza and fucking beer?
到池子里来 哥们
Get in the pool, man.
Perry中士 我得和这个人谈一谈
Sergeant Perry, I've gotta go talk to this guy,
所以你们可以自由活动一会儿
so you all are on your own for a little while.
收到
Roger that.
能喝杯啤酒吗?
Can we have beer?
没门
Not one.
所以 是怎么回事?
So, what happened?
我们正在目标点挖掘
We were digging at a site.
一个当地人跑来告诉我们
Local come up to us and give us a tip that there was a meeting going on
附近有一些高层的人正在开会
with some high-value targets nearby.
我们袭击了开会点 发现那人没撒谎 Al Rawi就在那儿
We hit the house, and it turned out the guy was right. Al Rawi was there.
- 你确定是他吗?  - 不会错的
- You sure it was him?  - Positive.
他有一群保镖跟着他 我们交了火
He had a security detail with him, and we exchanged fire with them
结果他趁乱逃走了
and he slipped out during the firefight.
这本书是我从一个叫Seyyed Hamza的人身上得到的
Now that's the book that I took off this guy, Seyyed Hamza.
会议是由他主持的
He was the host of the meeting.
我正想办法问清事情的原委
And I was in the process of figuring out what the fuck it was
结果特种部队冲了过来 就这么把他带走了
when SF showed up and snatched him.
真该死!
God damn!
是啊 可是他们把他押到哪了?
Okay, but where did they take him?
只要你能让我接近这个人
Because if you can get me access to this guy,
我就能抓到Al Rawi
I'll get Al Rawi.
我们都是为了找到大规模杀伤性武器 没错吧?
Look, we're both after the WMD, right?
事情其实没有你说的那么简单
It's a little more complicated than that.
但在我看来 不是这样
Well, not to me, it isn't.
好吧 我会打电话 让你重新分配到他那
All right, I'll make a call, get you reassigned.
这院子的另一边有很多空房子
There are some empty buildings on the other side of the compound.
脱掉制服 一小时后到我办公室报到
Get out of uniform and report to my office in an hour.
好极了
Outstanding.
鼻子怎么流血了?
How'd you get the bloody nose?
哦 那可说来话长了
Oh, that's a long story.
你是85师 那个大规模杀伤性武器搜寻部队 对吧?
You're in the 85th. That's WMD unit, right?
你怎么知道的?
How did you know that?
不就写在你步枪上面么
It's right there on your rifle.
我是Lawrie Dayne 华尔街日报的 搜查进行得如何?
Lawrie Dayne, Wall Street Journal, How's it going?
你知道的 我们什么都没找到 嘿 Perry中士
You know, we haven't found shit yet. Hey, Sergeant Perry.
一定会找到的 多少有点沮丧 不是么?
We'll find it. It's frustrating, right?
是有一点
Little bit.
刚才你跟Marty谈什么啊?
So what are you and Marty talking about?
哦 你该知道 我可不能跟你说那些
Oh, you know I can't talk to you about that.
哦 得了吧
Oh, come on.
你风尘仆仆地从战场跑来只是为了跟Martin Brown喝杯柠檬汽水?
You come in fresh off the field to have a lemonade with Martin Brown?
肯定是有什么事
Something's gotta be going on.
那你可以问他啊
Well, you could ask him.
我可是在问你
I'm asking you.
我们至今一无所获 你没觉得有问题吗?
Does it make sense to you that we're still coming up empty?
没有 没问题
No. No, it doesn't.
有人给我们说那儿有武器 对吧?
Someone told us they were there, right?
如果有什么发现
If you come across anything,
打给我
call me.
行 我记住了
I'll keep it in mind.
内部人士证实伊拉克有大规模杀伤武器计划
一位代号为"Magellan"的伊拉克高官
爆出令人震惊的伊拉克大规模杀伤武器计划
"Magellan" 说出了几个地点
位于迪瓦尼亚的肉毒杆菌毒素
曼索尔的地下存储网络
据信"Magellan"在一个秘密地点会见了一名美国高官
但具体细节仍属高度机密
他躲到哪去了? Al Rawi在哪啊?
Where's he hiding? Where's Al Rawi?
Al Rawi在哪啊?
Where's Al Rawi?
问了多久?
How long have they been going?
10分钟左右吧
For about 10 minutes.
你还想见到你的妻子和小孩吗? 你有五个孩子
You want to see your wife and kids again? You have five kids,
你还想让他们看见自己的父亲吗?
You want them to see their father?
他说"求你了 不要把我的家人牵扯进来"
He says, "Please, do not involve my family in this situation,"
"我对天发誓..."
"I swear to God..."
一旦你被扯进来了 你家人也就被扯进来了
You're involved, so your family's involved,
我只要你回答我 这个男人在哪
All I want is an answer, where to look for this man,
我就让你走
and you can walk out of here,
- Al Rawi在哪?  - Al Rawi在哪?
- Where's Al Rawi?  - Where's Al Rawi?
把名字或地址告诉我
And I want a name or an address,
告诉我在哪能找到Al Rawi将军
Somewhere I can find General Al Rawi,
我需要一个回答
I am going to get an answer,
而你也明白要告诉我点什么
and you know you're going to tell me something,
好吧 只要你告诉我一个地址 我就马上放你走
All right, I'm going to let go and you're going to give me an address,
Al Rawi在哪? 他到底在哪?
Where's Al Rawi? Where is he?
那本书! 那本书!
The book! The book!
他说你需要一本书
He says you need the book,
又是那该死的书? 书里有什么?
The fucking book again? What's in the book?
"那本书 它能帮你找到他"
"The book, that's how you'll find him,"
书上有Al Rawi藏身处的名称和地点
It has the names and locations of Al Rawi's safe houses,
Miller准尉在吗?
Chief Miller around?
在 上楼右转就是
Yeah. Up the stairs, down on the right.
嘿 准尉 我是Clark Poundstone 五角大楼特殊情报局的
Hey, Chief, Clark Poundstone, Pentagon Special Intelligence Unit.
抓Hamza干得可是真漂亮啊
A great job bagging Hamza.
谢谢 非常感谢
Thanks. Appreciate it.
边走边说?
Walk you out?
好的
Sure.
- 你是咱们机动执行组部队的 对吧?  - 是的
- You're with our MET Team, right?  - Yeah.
管理层非常感激你们所做的工作
Well, the administration really appreciates the work you guys are doing.
我们得把这个大规模杀伤性武器的事情往后放一放
We gotta get this WMD issue behind us
这样才能迎接未来更为重要的挑战
so we can get on with the challenges of the future.
这个Hamza正好能够帮上忙
That's where this Hamza guy could be helpful.
他向我们供认了一些事实
He's confirmed a few facts for us.
还说你们好像捡到了他掉的一个笔记本
Says your guys might have lifted a notebook from him.
但是 我从他身上得到的东西可都给了Martin Brown
Well, everything I got off him I gave to Martin Brown.
你为什么不去问问看他拿了没?
Why don't you ask him if he's got it?
我可不认为Marty会那么做
I don't think Marty would go for that.
他是个了不起的人 但也是在中东待了很久
He's a hell of a guy, but he's been in the Middle East a long time.
有很多的成见
He's got a lot of preconceived ideas.
我们局正努力寻找着第一手情报
Our unit's trying to get back to the raw intel.
你看 我可不是想说Marty的坏话
Look, I don't want to throw Marty under a bus,
但是他不喜欢我们提出的意见
but he doesn't like what we're coming up with.
那家伙不合时宜
The guy's a dinosaur,
但是我们需要更多的信息
and we need to get some new thinking going on around here.
我这有个机会给你 Mliier
There's an opportunity for you here, Miller.
我知道Marty暂时把你调了进来
I know Marty's pulled you in temporarily,
但是如果你想待得更长更久的话 我能帮上你
but if you're looking for something more permanent, I can help.
我们做的可是好事 我可是准备要重建这个地区
We're doing a good thing here. We're going to rebuild this place.
人民可都在看着我们啊
People are watching us.
行 我记住了
I'll keep it in mind.
一定要记好
You do that.
如果你有了笔记本的消息 转告我一声啊
If you hear anything about that notebook, let me know.
你一位在五角大楼的朋友来找过我
Your friend from the Pentagon Special Intelligence Unit came to see me.
Poundstone吗?
Poundstone?
是的 Poundstone
Yeah, Poundstone.
你们之前追踪的大规模杀伤性武器情报都是Poundstone的人提供的
Poundstone's unit pushed all that WMD intel you've been chasing your tail on.
什么? 你是说Magellan?
What? You mean Magellan?
Magellan是谁? 你跟他见过面吗?
Who is Magellan? Have you ever met him?
没见过
No.
Poundstone把他关得紧紧的
Poundstone's got him locked up tight.
这就是我们得把它调查清楚的原因
That's why we gotta find out what's going on.
情况是这样的
Here's the deal.
我们调查过了笔记本
We checked the notebook.
上面记录着巴格达附近的地址 主要在Adhamiya那块
It's a list of addresses around Baghdad, mostly Adhamiya.
那是个伊斯兰逊尼派教徒的大本营 同情军队
It's a Sunni stronghold, very sympathetic to the army.
十有八九 Al Rawi就躲在那
More than likely, that's where Al Rawi is.
那个笔记本也许就是他和他部下联系的方式
The notebook's probably his line to his battalion commanders.
都准备好了吗?
We all set?
还没 我们正在等军队的支持
Not yet. We're waiting on military support.
使劲催他们 我要那本书上的每个地址都被搜查到
Push them hard. I want to get every address in that book.
那么 你觉得那个会议在讨论些什么?
So, what do you think that meeting was about?
你要是被入侵了 会第一时间讨论什么呢?
What would you be talking about if you just got invaded?
你觉得Al Rawi想开战?
You think Al Rawi wants to fight?
如果我们不给他谈条件的话 就会的
If we don't make him an offer, he will.
什么? 你们想跟他协商条件?
What? You're going to cut a deal?
你们想跟梅花J来谈条件?
You're going to cut a deal with the Jack of Clubs?
你觉得你来这都是为了什么 Miller?
What do you think you're doing here, Miller?
你为了一个目标而来的这里 什么目标?
You're off reservation for a reason. What is it?
我来这是为了找武器救人命的
Well, I came to find weapons and save lives.
但是我什么也没找到
And I didn't find shit.
我想知道为什么
I want to know why.
这不是一两句话就能说清楚的 想要简单答案的话 你找Poundstone去好了
There are no easy answers. If you want that, go work with Poundstone.
我们有的只是艰难的抉择
All we got is hard choices.
你想要知道武器情报是怎么回事吗?
You want to know what happened to the weapons?
我们得把Al Rawi找到 并把他带过来
We gotta find Al Rawi and bring him in.
他会告诉我们大规模杀伤性武器的真相
He'll give us the truth about WMD
还有怎样才能避免大屠杀并且重建好这个国家
and give us a shot at standing this country up without a bloodbath.
你干还是不干?
Do you want the job or not?
- 好吧 我干  - 很好
- Yeah, I want it.  - Good.
Hamza被关在Cropper兵营的要犯区
Hamza's being held at the high-value target wing at Camp Cropper.
Poundstone的人把他藏匿起来了
Poundstone's unit have him under wraps.
那么 你想怎样把他给找出来?
So, how are you going to get to him?
不是我找 是你找
I'm not. You are.
这是通行证
Here's a pass.
我们在那有另外一个犯人 你能利用他进去
We've got another prisoner there we can use to get you in.
他只是个低级别的共和国卫队 他们不会注意的
Low-level Republican Guard, way below their radar.
利用他作为借口 接近Hamza
Use him as an excuse to get to Hamza.
这里有一百万美元的现金
Here's a million dollars in cash.
告诉他 只要他告诉我们 钱就是他的了
Tell Hamza the money's his if he gives us what we need.
你告诉他 只要告诉我Al Rawi在哪
You tell him if he gives Al Rawi to me,
不过在我找到Al Rawi之前别说出来
keeps his mouth shut over there until I bring him in,
这周末我会把他和他的家人弄出国
I'll have him and his family out of the country by the end of the week.
你要我告诉他别对美国审讯人招供?
You want me to tell him to not talk to the American interrogators?
对
That's right.
我以为我们都是一条船上的呢
I thought we were all on the same side.
别幼稚了
Don't be naive.
Miller啊
Miller.
五角大楼刚刚取消了的调令
Pentagon just revoked your transfer.
遣返你回你原来的部队 即刻生效
You're being released back to your unit, effective immediately.
你站错队了
You chose the wrong side.
跟我来 Freddy 我们得快点行动
Follow me, Freddy. We gotta move fast.
你们以为你们这是去哪?
Where do you think you're going?
让我们过去 请让开
Let us through. Step aside, please.
你到底在玩什么把戏? 联系Langley
What the hell are you playing at? Get me Langley.
你要提交所有信息
You are required to hand over all information.
白宫授权 我要笔记本
White House authorization. I want the book.
这个对华盛顿太重要了 不能被你和一些复兴党将军搞砸了
DC's got too much riding on this to have you and some Ba'athist generals fuck it up.
Martin啊
Martin.
Langley确认了
Langley confirms.
找到了!
I've got it!
咱们走 别再插手这事了 Marty
Let's go. Stay out of this, Marty.
- 你还好吧?  - 没事
- You all right here?  - Yeah.
用当地人
Use local assets.
这是当务之急
It's high priority.
"帮助我们将伊拉克推向美好的未来"
"为了自己 为了你的家人 为了你的国家 请合作"
跟紧我 Freddy
Stay close to me, Freddy.
把他弄下来
Put him down.
中情局
OGA.
我来看个犯人
I'm here to see a prisoner.
- 抬头 Sarge  - 嘿 中士
- Heads up, Sarge.  - Hey, Sergeant.
你好 长官
Hello, sir.
我来见Abdullah Ferat
I'm here to see Abdullah Ferat.
我要检查你的包
I'm gonna have to search your bag.
这伊斯兰教徒是谁?
What's up with Hajji?
他是我的翻译
He's my translator.
胳膊抬起 腿分开
Arms up, legs apart.
检查一下
Check it out.
你口袋里是什么?
What's that in your pocket?
香烟
It's my cigarettes.
- 没问题  - 给你 长官
- Good to go.  - Here you go, sir.
带他们去 一会再把他们带回IR-1区
Go ahead and take them back to IR-1.
就是这儿
Right here.
没必要这样 中士
That's not necessary, Sergeant.
标准程序 长官
Standard procedure, sir.
中士 我和囚犯的谈话属于机密
Sergeant, I have to have a classified conversation with the prisoner.
你可以先出去等着
You can go on and step outside.
是的 长官 我在外面等着
Roger, sir. Be right outside.
你知道为什么他们把他抓到这儿吗?
Do you know why they brought him here?
因为他是共和国护卫队的 Freddy
He's here because he's in the Republican Guard, Freddy.
嘿 中士
Hey, Sergeant.
嘿 听着 这家伙刚刚透露了一条情报
Hey, listen, this guy just gave us a piece of intel.
你们的要犯区有个叫Seyyed Hamza的囚犯
You apparently have a prisoner in your HVT wing here named Seyyed Hamza.
他能帮我指认他
He can ID him for me.
我得把他弄到这儿来 快速指认一下
I gotta get him down here and ID him real quick.
那你需要EJ-75授权 伙计
You're going to need an EJ-75 for that, man.
伙计 我现在有一项军事行动
Guys, I got a live op going.
有一队士兵待命等着朝目标前进呢 我现在就得进行
I got a team in place ready to move on a target. I gotta do this now.
要花多长时间?
How long will it take?
两分钟
Two minutes.
- 就两分钟?  - 就是这样 两分钟而已 拜托
- Just two minutes?  - That's it. Two minutes. Come on.
- 好吧  - 好 我们走 嘿 Freddy
- All right.  - Good, let's go. Hey, Freddy.
把套子套在他们头上
Put those bags on their heads.
中情局来确认一下身份
OGA coming in for an ID check.
嘿 Hamza
Hey, Hamza.
起来
Get up.
靠
Shit.
叫医生来!
Get a medic!
我说 叫医生来!
I said, get a medic!
嘿 打电话叫医生 我们这有情况
Hey, get the medics on the phone. We've got a situation here.
他说 "你们为什么要这么对我?"
He say, "Why did you do this to me?"
他说会面时你们要求的一切 将军都照做了
He say the general did everything you ask of him in the meeting.
你什么... 什么会面?
What do you... What meeting?
什么会面?
What meeting?
他刚才说约旦
He just say Jordan.
让开! 让开!
Clear the way! Clear the way!
这儿怎么了 Miller?
What is going on here, Miller?
过来! 好的
Coming through! Okay.
他说"约旦"是什么意思?
What does he mean, "Jordan"?
得赶紧止血 他的脉搏太弱了
We gotta stop the bleeding. His pulse is weak.
准备好了吗?
我们5分钟后吃饭
Mohammed Al Rawi在那里?
我不知道
我要跟你谈谈Magellan的事
I need to talk to you about Magellan.
我一会给你打回去
I'm going to call you right back.
你知道什么了?
What you got?
我看了你的文章
I read your articles.
你说在战争之前有个叫Magellan的伊拉克大规模杀伤性武器
You said an Iraqi WMD source named Magellan
的情报线人和美国军官会面
met with US officials prior to the war.
我要知道那次会面的情况
I need to know about that meeting.
噢 不 拜托 Miller 我不能跟你说我线人的情况
Oh, no. Come on, Miller. I can't discuss my sources with you.
那 你见过那个人吗? 你知道他是谁吗?
Well, did you ever meet the guy? Do you know who he is?
我当然没见过他 天呐 他是个伊拉克人
Of course I didn't meet him. He's an Iraqi internal, for Christ's sake.
那你怎么知道他说的是真的?
Then how do you know what he's saying is true?
因为我通过一个可靠的中介人联系他
Because I made contact through a reliable intermediary.
- 可靠?  - 对
- Reliable?  - Yes.
那你去过Magellan提供的地点吗?
Have you ever even been to any of Magellan's sites?
你去过迪瓦尼亚吗? 提克里特呢?
You ever been to Diwaniya? Tikrit?
没
No.
那儿什么都没有
There's nothing there.
Magellan的情报是扯淡
Magellan's intel is bullshit.
中介人是谁?
Who's the intermediary?
不 我不会说我线人的情况 Miller
No. I'm not discussing sources, Miller.
上帝啊! 这可是我们开战的原因!
Jesus Christ! This is the reason we went to war!
好吧 那至少告诉我这事怎么回事
All right, then at least tell me how it happened.
这是怎么发生的?
How does this happen?
像你这样的人怎么会写出那些不实的报道来?
How does somebody like you write something that's not true?
告诉我!
Tell me!
你知道些什么?
What do you know?
有一天我接到一个华盛顿高官的电话
Look, I got a phone call one day from a senior official in DC.
他说 "我有个新闻"
He says, "I've got a story for you."
"萨达姆大规模杀伤性武器计划的真相"
"The truth about Saddam's WMD programs."
于是我就见了他
So I go to meet him.
他把线人的情报放到我手里
He puts the source report in my hands.
Magellan的报告 原始情报
Magellan's product, the raw intel.
那你什么时候检查情报真实性的?
But when do you check the story?
天呐 他可是高级官员
He was a senior official, for Christ's sake.
他有权直接盘问Magellan
He had access to Magellan's debrief.
他要求的就是我不能公开会议的地点
All he asked was that I not disclose the location of the meeting.
地点
The location.
对 以防危害到线人
Yes, in case I'd compromise the source.
是约旦 对吗?
It was Jordan, wasn't it?
会议在约旦进行的
The meeting was in Jordan.
对
Yes.
你可以留着你的百万美金了
You can keep your million dollars.
Al Rawi就是Magellan
Al Rawi's Magellan.
他们在盘问Magellan 他们严密关着他呢
They're debriefing Magellan. They've got him held tight.
假如他们没有呢?
Supposing they don't?
John 把钱收好
John, take care of the money.
Hamza说Al Rawi在约旦会见了美国官员
Hamza said Al Rawi met US officials in Jordan.
Dayne说Magellan在约旦会见了美国官员
Now Dayne said the same thing about Magellan.
这不仅仅是巧合
That's more than a coincidence.
有可能 可是说不通啊
Maybe. It doesn't make any sense.
如果Poundstone在约旦见了Al Rawi 那他隐瞒什么啊?
If Poundstone met Al Rawi in Jordan, what's he hiding?
那 要是他告诉他一些他不想听到的事呢?
Well, what if he told him something he didn't wanna hear?
如果他告诉他根本没有大规模杀伤性武器呢?
What if he told him there were no WMD?
我要Al Rawi在伊拉克境外的行动记录
I want Al Rawi's movements outside Iraq.
2003年的一月 二月 有什么发现
January, February, 2003. Anything you got.
我在查
I'm on it.
这就完全说通了 假情报
It all makes sense. The bad intel.
为什么我们在那些地点什么都没发现
Why our teams came up empty at those sites.
也许我们看错了
Maybe we're looking at this thing the wrong way around.
这只是猜想
It's a theory.
没真凭实据
You've got no proof.
别幼稚了
Don't be naive.
长官 2003年的2月5日 Mohammed Al Rawi在约旦的安曼
Sir, Mohammed Al Rawi was in Amman, Jordan on February 5th, 2003.
三天后网上就出现了Magellan
That's three days before Magellan came online.
查一下同时期Clark Poundstone的动向
Give me Clark Poundstone's movements, same period.
长官 同一天有一趟国防部的湾流飞机出行
Sir, we've got a DOD Gulfstream on the same date.
乘客Clark Poundstone从华盛顿特区前往约旦的安曼
Passenger Clark Poundstone routed Washington, DC to Amman, Jordan.
Martin 我们刚刚收到报告说 有一处Al Rawi藏身地受袭
Martin, we're getting reports of an attack on an Al Rawi safe house.
阿德哈米亚南部
South Adhamiya.
Poundstone在追杀Al Rawi 他不想让真相败露
Poundstone's hunting Al Rawi. He doesn't want the truth to get out.
我要知道下一个藏身地在哪
I need to know where the next safe house is.
站住
Mohammed Al Rawi在哪?
他在哪?
快说
就算我知道 也不会告诉你
全部清除了 准尉
All clear, Chief.
让Freddy过来!
Send Freddy!
是 长官! Freddy 行动
Yes, sir! Freddy, on the move.
Freddy  你来翻译
Freddy, I need you to translate.
告诉他 我需要他给Al Rawi将军带个信
Tell him I need to get a message to General Al Rawi.
告诉他 我要今夜和Al Rawi见面
Tell him I need to meet Al Rawi tonight.
Miller准尉有电话找您 长官
Chief Miller on the phone for you, sir.
- 喂?  - 我抓住了Tahir al-Malik
- Yeah?  - I got him,
一个Al Rawi军队的指挥官
Tahir al-Malik, one of Al Rawi's battalion commanders.
- 他在哪?  - 我放他走了
- Where is he?  - I let him go.
我让他给Al Rawi捎个信
Look, I told him to get a message to Al Rawi.
我告诉他 我今晚要和他在阿德哈米亚公交站见面
I told him I'd meet him at the Adhamiya bus station tonight.
如果我能把他活着带走 我们就有证据了
If I can bring him in alive, then we'll have our proof.
如果他说了 我们就知道大规模杀伤性武器的真相了
If he talks, then we'll get the truth about WMD,
好的 如果你见到Al Rawi 该说的都说给他听
All right, if you get in front of Al Rawi, offer him whatever you have to.
如果这事成了
If you pull this off,
我们还有机会 维持这里的安定
there's still a chance we can hold this place together,
我现在要出发了
I'm headed there now.
你真要和Mohammed Al Rawi协商?
You are serious to do a deal with Mohammed Al Rawi?
你知道他对这个国家的所作所为吗?
You know what already he do to this country?
我们只是想挽救生命 Freddy
We're just trying to save lives, Freddy.
有人认为他能终止叛乱
There are people who think he can stop an insurgency.
好吧 听着 我们前往阿德哈米亚
All right, listen up, we're going to Adhamiya.
但是听着 我们单独行动 所以 检查武器 检查通讯设备
But look, we're going alone, so weapons check, comms check.
确定你是最佳状态 我们没有后援
Make sure you're 100%. We got no support.
- 明白吗?  - 明白!
- Hooah?  - Hooah!
你还好吧? P中士 检查下无线电吧?
You okay? Sergeant P, can I get a radio check?
- 调一号频道  - Miller 你在做什么?
- Go to one.  - Miller, what you are doing?
- 一号频道  - 收到
- Channel one.  - Roger that.
看看发生的一切
Look at what's happening.
我只是要你今夜好好干活 Freddy
I just need you to do your job tonight, Freddy.
我们出发!
Let's roll!
长官...
他们杀了Qasim
说清楚
他们抓到我
但一个美国士兵救了我
他想见你 长官
这就是我们一直苦等的那个协议吗?
非常感谢你们 Kelly上将 Card上尉
Thank you all very much, Admiral Kelly, Captain Card,
以及亚伯拉罕 林肯号航空母舰的海军船员
officers and sailors of the USS Abraham Lincoln,
我的美国同胞
my fellow Americans,
伊拉克的主要战斗已经结束
Major combat operations in Iraq have ended,
在伊拉克战争中
In the battle of Iraq,
美国及我们的盟友已经胜利
the United States and our allies have prevailed.
太好了!
All right!
- 喂?  - 我是Briggs
- Yeah?  - This is Briggs,
我们有麻烦了
we got a problem.
我的当地人手下被杀了
My local assets are down.
有报告说是美国军方带他们出去 但未上报
I got a report saying it was US Army took them out and nobody called it in.
Miller在哪?
Where's Miller?
等一下
Stand by.
好的 听着 大家查一下蓝色追踪系统
All right, listen up. I need everybody on a Blue Force Tracker.
跟踪机动三角洲队 85师 XTF
Met-Delta 85th, XTF.
长官
Sir.
他正朝西北方向的阿德哈米亚前进
He's moving northwest towards Adhamiya.
- 预计抵达时间?  - 12分钟 长官
- ETA?  - Twelve minutes, sir.
预计抵达时间 12分钟
ETA, 12 minutes.
他要去见Al Rawi
He's meeting with Al Rawi.
妈的 他已经在路上了
Son of a bitch. He's on his way there right now.
好吧 你要我怎么做?
All right, what do you want me to do?
跟着Miller 他正好把带你到他那儿
Follow Miller. He'll lead you right to him.
发现Al Rawi后 把他妈的干掉
And when you find Al Rawi, you take that son of a bitch out.
Miller呢?
What about Miller?
他任期已满 不能带走Al Rawi
He's off reservation, Miller can't bring in Al Rawi,
别让他妨碍你
Don't let him get in the way.
我要发表那个声明
I want to make that announcement.
- 现在?  - 快发表!
- Now?  - Just make it happen!
这里是先锋6号空中指令
This is Vanguard 6 on the airborne command.
我需要一架C-2直升机监视全阿德哈米亚
I need a C-2 bird with eyes over Adhamiya.
我需要监听半径3英里内的所有
I want an ISO on all military radio
军事无线电频率和手机传输信号
and cell phone transmissions for a three-mile radius.
先锋6号 呼叫阿尔法1号 先锋6号 呼叫阿尔法1号
Alpha 1, this is Vanguard 6, Alpha 1, this is Vanguard 6,
先锋6号 我是阿尔法1号
Vanguard 6, this is Alpha 1.
阿尔法1号 我要你立刻转向阿德哈米亚中心地带
Alpha 1, I need you to divert to Adhamiya Central immediately,
锁定紧要目标 Mohammed Al Rawi
We have a high-value target identified, Mohammed Al Rawi.
格杀勿论
This is a kill, no capture mission.
收到
Roger that.
他们来了
Here they are.
行 我这就跟他讲 我们这就来
Yeah, I'll tell him. We're on our way.
Poundstone要在楼下召开新闻简报会
Poundstone's just called a press briefing downstairs.
Marty 大新闻
It's something big, Marty.
汽车站就在那边
This is the bus station. It's just over there.
兵分两路
Stagger two teams.
我穿过街道到那边的售货亭
I'm going to move across to the kiosk.
三十秒后 你们跟上
You give me 30 seconds to get across, then follow.
有人出现了 叫我跟上
Someone just showed up. I'm going to follow.
两分钟 大家准备 两分钟后开始发表声明
Two minutes, people, Two minutes to the announcement,
他离开大道 向西去了
He's going out the central alley, west.
很感谢大家在仓促之下赶来
Thank you all for coming at such short notice,
我们有一个重要宣告
We have a major announcement,
我们的行为与我们的承诺一致
This follows in lockstep with our commitment
致力于消除萨达姆的暴虐统治
to eliminate the tyranny of Saddam Hussein
以及尽快把伊拉克转型成一个现代民主国家
and expeditiously transform Iraq into a modern, functioning democracy,
Bremer大使刚已经签署命令
Ambassador Bremer has just signed an order
立即解散伊拉克现存武装力量
immediately disbanding Iraq's remaining military forces,
临时联合政府当局特此结束
The Coalition Provisional Authority hereby dissolves
伊拉克的全部武装力量 准军事部队
the entirety of Iraq's military and paramilitary forces,
以及国防部队
ministries of defense,
情报处 军务处 国家情报安全局
information, military affairs, intelligence and national security,
所有官员 士兵 应招士兵
all officers, soldiers, conscripts
以及其他的军用人员就地解职
and other military figures are relieved of duty,
废除所有军衔 头衔 军籍
all military ranks, titles and status are canceled,
此外 裁定立刻取缔伊拉克执政的复兴党
in addition, Iraq's ruling Ba'ath Party is dissolved with immediate effect,
其党员立即从中央到地方政府办事处
Party members will be summarily fired from central and local government offices,
医院 大学 中小学以及其他公立机构解除职务
hospitals, universities, schools and other public institutions,
伊拉克迎接领导新秩序 让全世界见证
this is the dawn of new leadership in Iraq, and let the world take note,
中东即将新变革
change is coming to the Middle East at last,
一直往西南走 往西南
Still moving southwest. Southwest.
收到
Copy that,
你看见他了?
You got him?
是的 我看见他了
Yeah, I see him.
我失去目标了
I lost contact.
失去目标了
妈的! 中计了!
Fuck! Get an angle!
妈的 他在那车里
Fuck, he's in the vehicle.
- 我操!  - 跟上准尉!
- God damn it!  - Stay on Chief!
他们到底想去哪?
Where the fuck did they go?
他是不是在那车上?
Did he get in the vehicle?
跟上它! 跟上它! 这是机动部队D小组
Let's go! Let's go! This is MET Team "D."
我们需要支援 美军士兵遭劫持!
We need help, American soldier kidnapped!
我们这需要协助!
We need help down here!
所有部队注意 我们需要在阿德哈米亚区需要协助
All units, we need help in the Adhamiya district,
收到 机动部队 我是先锋6号 TF221战机
Copy that, MET Team. This is Vanguard 6 and TF221.
你的方位及情况?
What's your position and status?
先锋6号 我们在阿德哈米亚区汽车站南边五个街区处
Vanguard 6, we're five blocks south of the Adhamiya bus station.
绑匪的两辆小车朝东逃匿
Kidnappers heading east in two small cars,
收到 机动部队D组 我正赶过去
Roger that. MetD, I am en route.
我要求你们回到自己的车上 等待下一步指示
I need you to return to your vehicles and await further instructions.
先锋6号呼叫 猎鹰16
Falcon 16, this is Vanguard 6.
有情况 美军官遭到劫持 我们需要立即追踪那些车!
We have a US soldier abducted. We need eyes on those vehicles now!
猎鹰16回复 先锋6号
Vanguard 6, this is Falcon 16.
所在位置为阿德哈米亚区东北两公里
Currently two klicks northeast of Adhamiya.
正在进行阿德哈米亚区地毯式搜索
Establishing an area of perimeter and sweeping Adhamiya.
87号区域 AT
AOR 87, Alpha Tango.
我们必须把他从那弄出来
We gotta get him out of there.
立刻联系Miller准尉
Get me Chief Miller now.
他们抓到他了 他妈的! 他们抓到他了
They've taken him. God damn it! They've taken him.
猎鹰16呼叫先锋6号
Vanguard 6, this is Falcon 16.
追踪到两辆车正快速移动
I've got your two vehicles moving rapidly.
两车刚驶入一车库
The two vehicles just entered a garage.
建筑物屋顶有一个大水塔
There's a large water tower on top of the building.
坐标为 KZ 8733 6428
Grid Kilo-Zulu-8732-6428.
- 阿尔法1号 我正降落 继续追踪目标  - 明白
- Alpha 1, I'm going in on foot. Continue to target.  - Acknowledge.
阿尔法1号 我们距离目标区域三公里
This is Alpha 1. We're three klicks from target area.
明白 找到离这一公里的降落区 让我降落
All right, put us down. Find an LZ a klick from here.
我要杀了你 大兵
你是谁?
Who are you?
将军 我叫Roy Miller
General, my name's Roy Miller.
我是美国陆军一级准尉
I'm a chief warrant officer with the US Army.
你想怎么样?
What do you want?
我要带你走
I came here to bring you in.
将军 我知道你在战前几周
General, I'm aware that you had contact with a US official
和一位美国官员接触过
in the weeks leading up to the war.
我想你已经准备好告诉他们 伊拉克的大规模杀伤性武器计划
I know you were ready to tell them everything about Iraq's WMD programs.
什么计划?
What programs?
没有任何计划
There are no programs.
我告诉过你们的官员
I told your official.
我们在91年后之后撤除了所有计划
We dismantled everything after 91s.
他告诉我们的政府 说你证实了仍在进行该计划
He told my government that you confirmed that the programs were still active.
他编造了你的情报 所以我们才会来这儿
He lied about what you said. That's why we're here.
有人核实了他的话吗?
Did anyone verify his story?
没有
No.
Miller先生 你的政府希望听到这个谎言
Your government wanted to hear the lie, Mr. Miller.
他们想铲除萨达姆 用尽一切手段
They wanted Saddam out, and they did exactly what they had to do.
这才是你们来的原因
This is why you are here.
行动
Go.
先锋6号呼叫阿尔法1号 告诉我你们的位置
Alpha 1, this is Vanguard 6, Give me your location,
阿尔法1号回复先锋6号
Vanguard 6, this is Alpha 1.
- 我们目标半公里外  - 分头行动
- We're half a klick away.  - Split up,
A组 从目标西侧进
Alpha team, take the west side,
B组 东侧进
Bravo team, take the east side of the objective.
我从北到南挺进 到达攻击地点等我
I got north-south. Move to assault positions. Wait for my go.
收到
Roger that,
那么你有什么话带给我吗?
So, do you have a message for me?
将军 要是你跟我走
General, if you come in with me,
在华盛顿同样有人愿意跟你合作
there are still people in Washington who will work with you.
人们清楚美国仍需要伊拉克军队的帮助
People who understand that we still need the Iraqi army
同心协力 共同建设
to hold this place together.
那为什么你的政府要解散伊拉克军队?
Then why is your government disbanding the Army?
宣布我们不合法
Making us outlaws.
又为什么要把伊拉克弄的分崩离析?
Why take Iraq apart piece by piece?
到底是为什么?
Why?
我冒着生命危险
I risked my life
说出大规模杀伤性武器的事实真相
to tell you the truth about WMD.
你们说: "说真话就新伊拉克就有你们一席之地"
"Tell the truth and you'll have a place in the new Iraq," they said.
那么Miller先生 我的一席之地在哪?
So where is my place, Mr. Miller?
在扑克牌上吗?
On a deck of cards?
Miller 你到底来干什么?
Why are you really here, Miller?
美国人来了！
快点！美国人来了！
你是来设计抓我的
You were supposed to lead me into a trap.
告诉我 他们准备怎么抓我
You will tell me now how they are planning to take me.
大家就位了?
Everybody in position?
先头B队就位
Vanguard Bravo in position.
先锋6号 B组就位
Vanguard 6, this is Bravo 1, We're ready,
先锋6号 A组就位
Vanguard 6, this is Alpha 1. We're in position.
将军 你一定要跟我走
You have to come in with me, General.
你反击我们 只会一败涂地
You will get nothing if you fight us.
你现在跟我走 还为时不晚
You have to come in now before it's too late.
就因为你们占领了巴格达
You think the war is over
你们就认为这场战争都结束了?
just because you are in Baghdad?
你会明白
You will see.
这只是个开始
It has only just begun.
行动
Let's go.
有手榴弹!
Grenade!
撤! 撤!
Go! Go!
美国人来了!他们进来了!
杀了他!
快! 动作快!
Come on! Move!
走 走
Let's go. Let's go.
有人倒下了! 快射屋顶!
Man down! Hit the rooftop!
快!
Go!
我们需要人手!
去! 保护埃米尔!
将军 这边走
安全! Stack死了!
Clear! Stack on Dutch!
快!
Go!
B组 左边 最后那个人跟着我 行动!
"B" Team, go left. Last guy with me. Let's go!
有情况
I've got something.
长官 有两敌人向东逃匿
Sir, I've got two hostiles headed east.
长官 还有一个 有一个友军在追捕
Sir, I got one more. There's one friendly in pursuit.
慢着!
Hold!
猎鹰16呼叫先锋6号
Vanguard 6, this is Falcon 16,
两敌军和一个友军已离开目标现场
Two hostiles and one friendly have exited target site
正在穿过你所在位置东北方向的巷子
and are now moving through alley northeast of your location.
密切观察该区域
Keep the area clear,
我正打开我应答器
I'm activating my transponder,
指引我进去 我要拦截他们
Bring me in. I want to cut them off.
趴下 趴下! 给我立刻趴下!
Down, get down! Get the fuck down!
猎鹰16呼叫先锋6号
Vanguard 6, this is Falcon 16.
目标已经甩掉友军 正往北移动
The targets have lost the friendly. Targets are now moving north.
左转四十五度去拦截
Turn 45 degrees to your left, maintain intercepting course.
这边! 转过来!
Turn! Turn!
我看不到目标了
I've lost visual contact.
我们来解决直升机!
发现直升机
我们把它引到广场去!
我来掩护你...
我发现他们了!
I've got them!
猎鹰16呼叫先锋6号
Vanguard 6, this is Falcon 16.
按目前的方向继续前进
Keep going your current direction.
目标穿过空地 向北移动
The target is crossing open ground, headed north.
火箭筒! 该死的!
RPG! Shit!
长官 这边走
走过来
Walk over.
站住
Stop there.
你确定 华盛顿想要的就是这些吗?
You sure this is what they want back in Washington?
放下武器!
Put that weapon down!
立刻 Freddy!
Now, Freddy!
你他妈干了什么?
What the fuck did you do?
这里不该由你们来控制
It is not for you to decide what happens here.
Freddy 离开这儿 回家去
Get out of here, Freddy. Go home.
我们将封锁这区域
We're gonna be locking this area down.
到时候这里会到处都是士兵
There are gonna be soldiers everywhere.
趁现在
Go home now,
快回家去
while you can.
一位高官
伪造情报
为战争找借口
你认为在没有逊尼派参与的情况下 能够组建一届成功的政府吗?
Do you think you can form a successful government without Sunni involvement?
这对伊拉克来说将会是个全新的开始
This is a new beginning for Iraq.
专政终结 自由新生
This is the end of tyranny and the beginning of freedom.
美国军事力量还会在伊拉克驻军多久?
How long will US forces be in Iraq?
需要多久就多久
As long as they are needed.
谢谢 就这些
Thank you. That's it.
- Clark  -Zubaidi先生
- Clark.  - Mr. Zubaidi.
今天是个伟大的日子
It's a great day.
确实 确实 很高兴见到你
Indeed, indeed. Good to see you.
- 欢迎  - 欢迎
- Welcome.  - Welcome.
- 你好吗 先生?  -不错 不错
- How are you, gentlemen? How are you?  - Good, good.
所以 是不是表示说不久将会有一场选举?
So, does this mean there's going to be an election soon?
现在缺乏民主力量
There's been a democracy deficit.
能解释下昨晚阿德哈米亚区的军事行动吗?
Can you comment about the action last night in Adhamiya?
Miller准尉
Chief Miller.
这份是我情报的复件 想当面交给你
It's a copy of my intel report. I wanted to give it to you personally.
谢谢 是来自Al Rawi?
Thank you. Is this Al Rawi?
是的
Yeah.
嗯 我听说了
Yeah, I heard about this.
这里言辞很激烈
There's some pretty strong language here.
但 Miller 这又什么意义呢?
But what's the point, Miller?
你认为大家都会听你的?
Do you think anybody's going to listen to you?
我知道是你的所作所为
I know what you did.
你说什么?
What did you say?
为达到目标 他是你捏造出来的
You made him up to get what you needed.
Magellan是你捏造出来的
Magellan. You made him up.
Miller 我不明白你说什么
I don't know what you're talking about, Miller.
当你在华盛顿散播谣言 他们就知道那是骗人的?
When you peddled that shit in DC, did they know it was a lie?
又或者只是他们都懒得去核实?
Or did they just never bother to ask?
行了吧 够了
Okay, okay.
拜托 没人会去关心了 大规模杀伤武器? 不再重要了
Come on, none of this matters anymore. WMD? This doesn't matter.
你他妈说什么鬼话? 这他妈当然重要
What the fuck are you talking about? Of course, it fucking matters.
参战原因当然重要!
The reasons we go to war always matter!
他妈的很重要 很他妈的重要
It's all that fucking matters. It fucking matters.
放松点 士兵
At ease, soldier.
你到底知不知道你干了什么?
Do you have any idea what you've done here?
要是下次我们需要人民的信任 那要怎么办?
What's going to happen next time we need people to trust us?
喂 Clark!
Clark!
Miller 没有回头路了
We're not turning back, Miller.
毕竟我们赢了
We won.
Clark啊!
Clark!
- 狗娘养的 -怎么回事?
- Son of a bitch.  -What?
这让人难以接受!
不支持就滚开!
拜托 先生们!
不要美国走狗来的统治!
伊拉克一定要有真正的伊拉克人来统治!
来自Roy Miller的邮件
这次我们报道真实的新闻 参见附件
大规模杀伤性武器的虚假情报 MAGELLAN真相大白于天下
发往各大新闻社电子邮箱